

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ESTEBAN PEDRAZA

CONTACT

www.estebanpedraza.co

in linkedin.com/in/estebanpedraza

TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML / CSS
- Bootstrap
- Angular 10+
- Angular Js
- JavaScript
- Git / GitHub
- SQL (Server, MySQL, Oracle)
- WordPress
- Java
- NodeJS
- C++
- C#
- Python
- Azure Cloud

LANGUAGES

- English | B2 Intermediate
- Spanish | C2 Native

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm a software developer with two years of experience working with development and mainteinance of websites and platforms for companies and institutions. I have worked and certified my experience with technologies such as Angular 10+, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, NodeJS and Java and therefore I'm available to work as a Front-end or Back-end developer.

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer - Bex Technology S.A.

NOVEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2021

- Front-end development of websites and platforms with MVC design patterns using technologies such as AngularJS, Angular 10+, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap y JavaScript.
- Data layer persistence using DBMS such as SQL Server and Oracle Server.
- Platform development using lists, libraries and active directory with Microsoft technologies such as Azure and Sharepoint.

Software Developer UI - Kantar Media

JUNE 2021 - AUGUST 2021

- Front-end and Back-end development of websites and platforms with MVC design patterns using Angular 10+, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript.
- Back-end maintenance of web platforms with technologies such as NodeJS.
- Data layer persistence using DBMS such as SQL Server and Oracle Server.

Java Developer - Globant Colombia

NOVEMBER 2021 - MARCH 2022

- Platform maintenance with microservices architecture based on NodeJS, Docker, Kubernetes and MySQL...
- Front-end maintenance of web platforms with Angular 10+.

WHAT AM I KNOWN FOR?

- Quick adaption to the work environment.
- Never stop learning.
- Always looking to form new connections and grow.

LEARNING PATH

React: Hooks and MERN Udemy | In progress

Microservices with NodeJS and React

Udemy | In progress

HOBBIES







EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Developer - CINTE Colombia

JULY 2022 - OCTOBER 2022

Client: IBM - Bancolombia

 Implement new features using SCRUM methodology for a insurance managing platform. Used tools: Microservices architecture developed with Spring Boot, AWS (EC2, Secrets, Buckets) and Angular 10.

EDUCATION

Pontificia Universidad Javeriana - Bogotá

JANUARY 2018 - DECEMBER 2023

- Implement software projects using design patterns.
- Perform and automate unit tests of software with JUnit and Sellenium.
- Design and construction of RestFul APIs.
- Knowledge about data structures and their usefulness to organize information as required.

Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje

JANUARY 2014 - DECEMBER 2015

 Build software from the requirements analysis bases, through design to implementation in real work environments.

CERTIFICATIONS

Angular 10+ Course

Udemy | November 2020

Git/GitHub Course

Udemy | November 2020

MySQL Bootcamp Course

Udemy | December 2020

NodeJS Course

Udemy | December 2020

Security management in Azure

IT Talent - Microsoft Partner | May 2020

EVENTS I'VE BEEN PART OF

Facebook Developers Hackaton | 2° Place February 2021

IBM - IEEE Bootcamp: Journey to CFC April 2021